It just takes a few good men.
Operation Dunkirk is a war, action film directed by Nick Lyon.
A band of soldiers tasked with staying behind during the Battle of Dunkirk to rescue a scientist with information that could
turn the tide of the war must battle their way through dangerous Nazi territory to complete their mission.
Lt. Galloway, played by Ifan Meredith.
Angelique, played by Kimberley Hews.
Strasser, played by Michael Wouters.
Sgt. Walker, played by Kyle Hotz.
Roger King, played by Tyler Cole.
Thomas, played by Conner P. Kelley.
Dunkirk is a 2017 historical war film produced, written, and directed by Christopher Nolan that depicts the
Dunkirk evacuation of World War II from the perspectives of people on the land, sea, and air.
It features an ensemble cast including Fionn Whitehead, Tom Glynn-Carney, Jack Lowden, Harry Styles in his feature film debut,
Aneurin Barnard, James D'Arcy, Barry Keoghan, Kenneth Branagh, Cillian Murphy, Mark Rylance, and Tom Hardy.
The film portrays the evacuation with little dialogue, as Nolan sought
instead to create suspense through cinematography and music.
Filming began in May 2016 in Dunkirk and wrapped that
September in Los Angeles, when post-production began.
Cinematographer Hoyte van Hoytema shot the film on IMAX
65 mm and 65 mm large-format film stock.
Dunkirk has extensive practical effects.
It employed thousands of extras as well as historic boats
from the evacuation, and period aeroplanes.
Distributed by Warner Bros.
Pictures, Dunkirk premiered at Odeon Leicester Square in London, a few days before
its release in the United Kingdom and United States on 21 July 2017.
It grossed over $530 million worldwide, making it the highest-grossing World War
II film until it was surpassed by Nolan's Oppenheimer (2023).
Dunkirk received praise for its screenplay, direction, editing, score, sound design and cinematography; some critics called
it Nolan's best work, and one of the greatest war films as well as one of the greatest movies of the 2010s.
It received various accolades, including eight nominations at the 90th
Academy Awards, including Best Picture and Best Director.
It went on to win for Best Sound Editing, Best
Sound Mixing, and Best Film Editing.
The film explores themes of nazi, world war ii, soldier, battle, scientist.